<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Machine Learned It Online</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Machine Learned It Online</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the i2dash R package for interactive visualisations</title>
      <link>/2020/07/28/using-the-i2dash-r-package-for-interactive-visualisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/28/using-the-i2dash-r-package-for-interactive-visualisations/</guid>
      <description>Keeping up with the huge range of R packages released and updates to existing packages can be time consuming and difficult, though important to monitor as there can be innovations that will save you time, if you are aware of them.
One of the recent releases is the i2dash package for interactive visualisations in R. Now how helpful this is for you may depend on your expertise (or not) in developing shiny web applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I add Google adsense code to my Blogdown Hugo site?</title>
      <link>/2020/07/20/how-do-i-add-google-adsense-code-to-my-blogdown-hugo-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/20/how-do-i-add-google-adsense-code-to-my-blogdown-hugo-site/</guid>
      <description>If you have started your own blog using Blogdown and Hugo, you might be wondering how to monetise your content to cover your operating costs. Sure, it may not be much but every little bit counts right.
Well, today is your lucky day because I wondered this too and decided to write a blog post about it giving you the instructions to add advertising to Blogdown Hugo sites.
So first things first, you will need to go and get an adsense account, which you can do here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny, for sharing web based data applications</title>
      <link>/2020/07/19/shiny-for-sharing-web-based-data-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/19/shiny-for-sharing-web-based-data-applications/</guid>
      <description>After learning R for a few months, the code wasn’t looking quite so much like gibberish and I was becoming more curious about how to share these data insights on a wider scale, other than a static report.
The challenge with the report approach of course is you spend time creating something for a specific scenario and if the business user has a resulting question, they may need to come back to you, with their query/request to view whatever it is they need and suddenly the business user is waiting for you, while you now have another task, to create another report with the specified one off metric and when that’s done, you’ll probably get another request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is the private blog of a Brisbane based Kiwi and amateur R data wrangler. I&amp;rsquo;m in my early 40&amp;rsquo;s with a couple of great kids and partner, living in the so affordable Brisbane burbs - this is the life and no doubt why there are so many silver fern stickers plastered on VN Commodores around here. Chur bro&amp;rsquo;s.
I blog, therefore I am and hey, it beats watching shitty tv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do I start to learn R?</title>
      <link>/2020/07/17/where-do-i-start-to-learn-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/17/where-do-i-start-to-learn-r/</guid>
      <description>Right now you may be in the same place I was about a year ago having decided I would learn R, then pondering where do I start to learn R? Because at heart I am the frugal tight arsed type, when looking for what options were available to start my journey, I did some research that might save you some time.
If you like to learn interactively, Datacamp is hard to go past, particularly if you take advantage of some of the free trial offers you might get signing up for active deals like this one that at the time of writing this gives you 2 months free access if you sign up with your details, plus some other goodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For me the choice was Python or R</title>
      <link>/2020/07/16/for-me-the-choice-was-python-or-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/16/for-me-the-choice-was-python-or-r/</guid>
      <description>Having decided to improve my capability in this space, I started to research available options. It became clear quite quickly that the choice would come down to Python or R for me, as both of these free and open sourced options had excellent reputations, fitted my budget and had a larged community of active users.
I can’t remember where I saw this tip but for me it was the decider and something worth sharing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World - Powered by R, Bookdown, Github, Hugo &amp; Netlify</title>
      <link>/2020/07/15/hello-world-powered-by-bookdown-hugo-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/15/hello-world-powered-by-bookdown-hugo-netlify/</guid>
      <description>But, why?Over the last year, I have been fortunate to have time to reflect and refocus on what is important to me personally and professionally, taking learnings away from a career in Retail Management, eCommerce Operations &amp;amp; Fulfilment.
Having had exposure to high level decision making in an eCommerce world inside a large multi brand corporate, it has become increasingly clear to me that handling big data to gain and share insights would be the next business frontier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Test Dashboard</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/my-test-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/my-test-dashboard/</guid>
      <description># Deal with operation within a switchr environmentif (any(grepl(pattern = &amp;quot;.switchr&amp;quot;, x = .libPaths()))) {switchr::switchrNoUnload(TRUE)}# Make it possible to reuse chunk labelsoptions(knitr.duplicate.label = &amp;quot;allow&amp;quot;)# Set datadir variable, components should fetch their env from here!datadir &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;C:/Users/mattr/OneDrive/Documents/R/themachinelearnedit.online&amp;quot;# Set up color mappingscolormaps &amp;lt;- list()Home PageColumnPlotly exampleif (!requireNamespace(&amp;quot;plotly&amp;quot;, quietly = TRUE)) {stop(&amp;#39;The package &amp;quot;plotly&amp;quot; is needed to embed objects of class &amp;quot;plotly&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>