<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shiny on The Machine Learned It Online</title>
    <link>/tags/shiny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shiny on The Machine Learned It Online</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/shiny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the i2dash R package for interactive visualisations</title>
      <link>/2020/07/28/using-the-i2dash-r-package-for-interactive-visualisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/28/using-the-i2dash-r-package-for-interactive-visualisations/</guid>
      <description>Keeping up with the huge range of R packages released and updates to existing packages can be time consuming and difficult, though important to monitor as there can be innovations that will save you time, if you are aware of them.
One of the recent releases is the i2dash package for interactive visualisations in R. Now how helpful this is for you may depend on your expertise (or not) in developing shiny web applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny, for sharing web based data applications</title>
      <link>/2020/07/19/shiny-for-sharing-web-based-data-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/19/shiny-for-sharing-web-based-data-applications/</guid>
      <description>After learning R for a few months, the code wasn’t looking quite so much like gibberish and I was becoming more curious about how to share these data insights on a wider scale, other than a static report.
The challenge with the report approach of course is you spend time creating something for a specific scenario and if the business user has a resulting question, they may need to come back to you, with their query/request to view whatever it is they need and suddenly the business user is waiting for you, while you now have another task, to create another report with the specified one off metric and when that’s done, you’ll probably get another request.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>